{
    "id": "c8a2fcedf69d44aab7c476d4e35fd19f",
    "title": "Hear and listen",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "01328a6ea02d48138bead4dd3281bd5a",
            "title": "Hear And Listen",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did you .............................. a noise now?",
                    "description": "To hear is to perceive something with the ear.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hear",
                        "listen",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "A large audience .................................. the concert last night.",
                    "description": "We generally use hear to talk about experiencing the whole of a performance or speech.",
                    "answers": [
                        "heard",
                        "listened",
                        "listened to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ................................. that you are moving to Switzerland.",
                    "description": "Hear can mean be informed or be told.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hear",
                        "listen"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I didn't ................................. the doorbell.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "listen",
                        "hear",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wish I had ......................................... his advice.",
                    "description": "To listen to something is to pay attention to it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "heard",
                        "listened",
                        "listened to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The judge will ................................... the case next month.",
                    "description": "To hear a case is to investigate it officially.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hear",
                        "listen",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is important. Please .................................. carefully.",
                    "description": "When there is no object, we use listen instead of listen to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "listen",
                        "hear",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Can you ................................. me properly?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "hear",
                        "listen",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don't know what he said. I was not ...................................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "hearing",
                        "listening",
                        "listening to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I .................................. someone knocking on the door.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "heard",
                        "listened",
                        "listened to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Please ………………………….. me. I am going to tell you something.",
                    "description": "Before an object, we use listen to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hear",
                        "listen",
                        "listen to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}